<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Tech Scribe</title>
    <link>https://luxury-mermaid-2fc6e2.netlify.app/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Tech Scribe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://luxury-mermaid-2fc6e2.netlify.app/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Merge PDFs Using Python</title>
      <link>https://luxury-mermaid-2fc6e2.netlify.app/posts/merge-pdfs-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 11:47:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luxury-mermaid-2fc6e2.netlify.app/posts/merge-pdfs-using-python/</guid>
      <description>Merge PDFs Using Python Working with PDF files can a pain&amp;hellip;but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be. You don&amp;rsquo;t even need any expensive software to do that: just a few lines of Python code will suffice.
In this quick tutorial I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to easily merge multiple files without having to tinker in the Adobe Acrobat or a similar program, simply taking advantage of the capabilities of the PyPDF2 library. This method is much quicker and cheaper and all the tools used here are free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Animation Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://luxury-mermaid-2fc6e2.netlify.app/posts/css-animation-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 16:02:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luxury-mermaid-2fc6e2.netlify.app/posts/css-animation-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Why create SVG animations using CSS? Animations created with JavaScript (or animated gifs) can become heavy and cause web pages to load slowly. SVGs are light and can be either referenced or embedded directly in the code. The clue to another advantage of using SVGs is in the name - Scalable Vector Graphics. They will look just as great on a tiny mobile screen as on a huge retina display. Thanks to the animation features in CSS3 we can create simple (yet enticing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxonomy</title>
      <link>https://luxury-mermaid-2fc6e2.netlify.app/posts/taxonomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 15:48:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luxury-mermaid-2fc6e2.netlify.app/posts/taxonomy/</guid>
      <description>Taxonomy Before you start: why should you create a taxonomy? Let&amp;rsquo;s be blunt: is a taxonomy necessary for your project? Why put extra work and effort into creating a system that many organizations seem to eschew? Let me illustrate with a quote from the kmworld Knowledge workers spend 15 to 35 percent of their time searching for information 40 percent cannot find the information they need on their corporate intranets 15 percent of their time is spent duplicating information that exists but cannot be found If the usability of a system can be improved, the time and effort that has been invested will result in time saved by everyone searching for information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readability</title>
      <link>https://luxury-mermaid-2fc6e2.netlify.app/posts/readability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 15:42:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luxury-mermaid-2fc6e2.netlify.app/posts/readability/</guid>
      <description>Legibility and readability can be easily confused. Let’s start with ‘legibility’, as the more important of the two. Legibility sipmly means that the text can be read. The contrast between the background and the font color is sufficient, the size is suitable, the letterforms can be easily distinguished.
A ‘readable’ text invites you to read. It goes beyond simple legibility. Usually, some clever formatting is needed to make the text readable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REST or SOAP</title>
      <link>https://luxury-mermaid-2fc6e2.netlify.app/posts/rest-or-soap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 12:01:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luxury-mermaid-2fc6e2.netlify.app/posts/rest-or-soap/</guid>
      <description>First of all, let us consider whether we can compare those web services. SOAP (Simple Object Access Protocol), as the full name suggests, is a protocol. On the other hand, REST is an architectural style. It allows more flexibility and is considered easier to implement. RESTful applications have become ubiquitous in recent years, with SOAP web services lagging behind. There is no simple answer to whether one is ‘better’ than the other - it depends on the use case.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
